[Music]
there's a lot of high-profile members of
the IDW you've been on the the Reuben
report a couple of times but you're
probably less well-known than say Ben
Shapiro Jordan Pederson Sam Harris
what's your your role within the IDW
that's a good question I would say
trying to anticipate what is likely to
come next and trying to position the
group so that it doesn't get torpedoed
by the usual mechanisms by which hopeful
things are removed from public
discussion like the IDW there was the
New York Times article that came out and
kind of named the IDW is there a kind of
paradox in it's no longer dark what was
never dark and that was a large part of
the joke we have only been dark to one
thing and that thing is the
institutional media and the main
platforms be they academic or
governmental so if you will I think that
the mainstream media has pretended not
to notice us as just as they pretended
to find it everything we say either
vapid there or outrageous so well they
try right to be both offended and claim
that its content free and not
interesting but I think that you know
what's really going on is that there's
been a monopoly effectively on narrative
held by the collection of major
institutional voices and to some extent
you have something like Fox News versus
NPR and those are going to be different
flavors but to a remarkable extent even
those two voices are remarkably agreed
on things that I don't think the rest of
us should be agreed on and so the true
spectrum of thought
is far broader than people have been led
to believe and I think that's where the
IDW comes in that we are it's not that
we're just outside of the Overton Window
many of the points we're making really
aren't found anywhere inside of
mainstream media and established
institutions even though many of these
things that we are talking about are
simply commonplace observations did you
have any doubts about that New York
Times article I mean I had I had an
infinite number of doubts about the New
York Times article the issue well
there's a conflict part of me wants to
work quietly and part of me realizes
that we have to work in some public
facing capacity and I personally have
found it much more comfortable to have a
private life to not have everything that
I'm thinking broadcast to a large
audience but I think we've run out of
time and so I think some of us are
somewhat reluctantly choosing to make a
different call now I think that with the
current administration and the White
House you're seeing a real discontinuity
with the past and it wasn't the
discontinuity that I was hoping for we
had to break with the past and I think
that the way in which we are now
breaking with the past is so destructive
nobody knows what to believe nobody
quite knows what's true nobody knows
where to turn
this is not a tenable situation and so
either we're going to descend into some
kind of permanent chaos or there is
going to be have to be something that we
reboot from and that thing cannot be
simply left or simply right and that's
one of the reasons the IDW is hopeful to
me is that it's a collection of people
who agree really on what a conversation
sounds like and and that's important
because ultimately you have to self
referee it's not like there's a
different species of person that's going
to referee conversations you can't tell
whether one point carried the day by
listening to
versus NPR because those two sets of
referees might disagree as to who made
the better point you need a group of
people who are willing to say hey you
know you made a better point and I've
changed my mind and I've learned
something that I didn't think about and
that kind of integrity in a conversation
is what characterizes a lot of the
internal IDW discussion to me it's that
people agree not on their positions they
may not even agree as to what the facts
are but they usually agree as to what
constitutes a conversation I'd say I
mean as an outside observer being also
sort of caught up in the excitement
what's amazing is that kind of almost
seeing the conversation becomes
self-aware on the Rubin report this sort
of sense of Dave Rubin in particular is
kind of like something's going on
something's happening and you call it a
conversation it's also it seems it's
also modeling what thinking looks like
what genuine thinking looks like where
there's a sense of your mind could be
changed by this conversation it and that
I guess is is showing how thirsty maybe
we are for that sort of sense of genuine
inquiry and genuine thinking I think
Dave in particular is very moved by
being out on the road both going and
touring his own comedy club appearances
and also opening for Jordan Peterson and
he's insisted that I follow him and a
couple of occasions onto the stage and I
now understand what he's talking about
he people are coming up after these gigs
and saying I'm afraid to express what
you expressed thank you for doing it I'm
almost at the point where I feel
comfortable but I lost a couple of
friends and some relatives who won't
talk to me anymore like well what did
you say the person might have said
something as innocuous as I'm not
convinced that there aren't biological
differences between women and you're
trying to imagine a world in which this
constitutes a controversial position of
course what's really going on is that
people are very worried about what the
consequences are of simply observing
reality so for example if you observe
that there's a lot of discussion
around immigration which synonymous 'as
any desire to hold a border with being
somehow afraid of other cultures that's
a crazy position to be in because almost
everybody agrees that borders are
important that citizenship matters and
that not everybody can be a citizen of
every country yet somehow to voice even
something so simple as I want a border
and I want may want fewer immigrants
rather than more immigrants that person
is now held up as if they've said
something about their own sense of their
country's superiority and jingoist
they're they're confused for being
jingoistic or xenophobic or anything
like this
so we've gotten to a completely crazy
state whereby people who hold absolutely
garden-variety
common sense viewpoints are seeing
themselves reflected in the media as if
in a funhouse mirror and they're seeing
themselves come back so distorted and
ugly that they're asking like what just
happened I fell asleep for a few years
and I wake up Rick Van Rip Van Winkle
style and I'm in a world in which
suddenly I'm the bad guy for simply
holding very commonplace ideas now those
people are so excited to see
conversations taking place with decency
with with you know comity and equanimity
so that these positions are not held in
an ugly fashion but they're simply
seeing a conversation take place that
they remember or that they dreamed was
possible and they're not seeing it
reflected anywhere else I think that's
what's what's really exciting is is that
the IDW conversation is the public front
of a national conversation that is
bizarrely taking place in hushed
whispers with people metaphorically
living in closets not ready to jump out
and declare hey I have some beliefs that
you are going to find shocking but to me
are absolutely garden-variety believes
the counter-argument to that would be
that actually the writer in power at the
moment
you look at what Trump is doing with the
the children in cages and all of that
sort of thing
so there is a political movement where a
lot of these things are actually
happening well I don't see I don't
really believe that what I believe is
that you've starved people for any
ability to make a very simple point
all right so for example imagine that we
analogize the country to a house and the
key question was should we allow people
to come for dinner like a visitor so
that would be like a tourist visa or a
temporary worker so now we have an issue
where every person who comes for dinner
somebody in the family wants to give
them a key and to formally adopt them
into the family well some members of the
family are saying where were we whoa
slow down
we know we're just having visitors over
for dinner and maybe we could adopt a
child but this is not something that we
want to do in an uncontrolled fashion
suddenly that being told by the couple
members of the family who wants sky-high
adoption inside of the family that these
are bad people and that they're bigoted
and etc etcetera well you're gonna have
an absolutely embittered angry group of
people who are who are saying look this
is a home and we're generous people but
adoption I mean you you're gonna dilute
all of us in some fashion well this is a
mirror of the national conversation and
what you're hearing is not the same
astronomers n ting a restriction
you're getting the only people who are
so incensed I guess in such a
desensitized State that they're going to
make terrible arguments for holding up
borders or enforcing visas and not
pushing everybody towards it on a path
toward citizenship so that's really
what's going on is is that you're seeing
a very bad version of restriction ISM in
the White House because that's all
that's been offered by the system but
what is the IDW it's going to give you a
completely different alternative it's
going to say look other cultures are
super exciting we're deaf
going to have some immigration and some
of it's good for our country some of its
good for the UK but what is that level
maybe that level should go up maybe that
level should go down it has zero to do
with xenophobia it has to do with
legitimate interests of a country people
not wanting to be diluted people wanting
to have something of their own culture
that they can bring to the international
potluck and not being told that their
substrate culture is somehow deficient
and that every culture that's coming in
should be held up and celebrated I mean
that's pretty common sense I don't
understand in any way shape or form why
we've gotten to a place where the only
people who can sort of talk in public
are either very far
you know jingoistic far far gone
jingoistic restriction estai negro of
people in the IDW who are going to say
this doesn't make a lot of sense and
you've described this as a civil war
within the left could you could you
explain what you mean by that
um sure I mean I think that the the left
that I relate to is the left that
realizes that the past cannot supply the
answers and that we have to actually
progress because we can't stay here it
is not the left that believes we can
wish ourselves into a beautiful future
by pretending that the reap that the
world is different than it actually is
so I think that the key thing that it is
an agreement between these two groups is
that we have to get to some sort of
better place and that is that the
progressive in progressivism where we
are deeply divided and you know again
these are the divisions that are is much
worse than between left and right
how these absolutely
imbecilic figures believe that you can
just wish yourself into paradise that
you don't have to worry about markets
that you can just say you know free good
things for everybody well it just
doesn't make a whit of sense or you know
you're going to wish human beings to be
both simultaneously non-diverse so that
you can argue that
any difference in pro-rata shares of a
group in any occupation is evidence of
oppression and then you're going to turn
around and argue that people are
actually incredibly different because
we're gonna get a huge benefit from
diversity I mean this is not even self
consistent this is this would be
offensive to an intelligent
five-year-old so I don't really believe
that these progressives as they call
themselves and regressives as some of us
call them are even making serious
intellectual points they're sort of
trolling by pretending to believe in all
things that just gum up the works and so
it's very important to me that not only
do we not really spend time debating
people who are not serious in their
intellectualism but that we realize that
it is important to the diversity of
mature and important ideas that we not
spend undue effort engaging ideas that
are functioning very differently from
regular conversation it is as if
somebody asks should we have a diverse
dinner tonight well we could invite
somebody from this position from that
country from this gender and then should
we should we invite a suicide bomber
well if you're a suicide bomber you're
that bit of diversity is going to take
down the entire conversation and as well
as all the people at the table right
well these are like suicide bombers in
terms of their ideas they are attaching
themselves to real conversations and
blowing up the conversation so that you
can't actually speak and I think what we
need is we need to realize that the
diversity of ideas that have to be
explored hinges are not allowing in bad
diversity that is you don't want a
single person at the table who wants to
scuttle the conversation and that's not
something that we've understood about
the modern left the modern left is very
often focused on scuttling any realistic
conversation so that it can continue to
threaten and terrorize people into
pretending to hold positions that no
sane person could possibly hold why do
you think it's become like this well I
think my wife probably has the best
explanation which is that when you're
actually dependent on labor for your
voter base labour has economic issues so
this is the great search for something
cheaper than labour and identity turns
out to be much cheaper than labour if
you can get somebody to vote for you
where you're gonna take their future
their security and their retirement but
you're going to celebrate the fact you
know that they came from Laos that's a
bad deal nothing against the Laotians
but for God's sake stand up for yourself
as a worker before you you know stand up
for yourself as somebody who needs to
see Southeast Asia celebrated on the
national stage it's not that exciting
demand more from from your
representatives this is the great search
for the cheapest possible constituency
and that's exactly why I think it's
happening I think it's because the
traditional Democratic voter base was
too expensive they wanted real change
they wanted to participate economically
they wanted to participate at the level
of power and the the donor base said is
there isn't there anything cheaper than
labour and I think they found something
do you see the IDW is primarily a
political project no I don't I see it
primarily as a precursor to anything
decent it's what has to succeed for us
to have a political conversation I don't
think we're having a political
conversation either internationally or
nationally I think we have people who
are talking about nonsense positions we
just went back to the immigration
position there are only two positions
I'm convinced aren't political one is
open borders which is never going to
happen and the other one is closed
borders which is never going to happen
and yet you very often encounter people
who are talking in these terms as if
these are the actual positions so I
don't think that we have
political conversation I think that
what's been going on is is that the
mainstream media has been playing
keep-away ball right so this game where
you're throwing the ball over somebody
who's trying to catch it now the public
had been trying to get in on this
conversation but what keeps happening is
is that our fake left and our fake right
are engaged in a completely fake
conversation about fake items including
fake news which they themselves are
pushing out and then claiming to fight
fake news so the whole thing is so
saturated in falsehood that people are
waking up to the idea ohm I forgotten
what it sound sounded like for people to
actually have a discussion about a topic
and how much time it takes you know in
general it can't be done with four or
five voices on a panel in 10 minutes
with a few commercial interruptions
there's just almost nothing can be
discussed that way and what's what's
worse is that the very people who would
be best able to discuss it are never
going to be invited on to those programs
and how would you describe your
political background I understand from
reading your Bernie supporter yeah I
mean I think we had two tariffs that we
had to three terrible candidates and I
thought Bernie was absolutely the least
bad of the three but none of those
people were fit for the White House I
mean Donald Trump is by far too erratic
and too destructive to the to the fabric
of the country Hillary is absolutely too
engaged in some sort of machine that is
being cynically operated for the few at
the expense of the many
and Bernie's ideas about economic reform
didn't make any sense by I simply
thought that he was the most decent of
the three and that we could easily
survive four years of a Sanders
presidency that might be kind of
confused on economic issues but with a
big heart and with somebody who was bold
enough to claim socialism as his mantle
inside of the United States which is
insane so that you know he was
individualistic enough and my feeling
was that was the softest landing and
that the Hillary option and the Trump
option were
you know nearly catastrophic for this
political process and you you said
earlier that you think the reason that
you're speaking out now the reason that
you're sort of taking more of a profile
is that you realize things have got to a
certain point you said I think you said
time is running out can you explain what
you think that means sure I mean for one
thing you know we've gone since the
early 50s with no one having used a
hydrogen device and anger against
another people I don't want to lose that
track record with people working out
fantasies of machismo with toys and
weapons that we've designed we in the
scientific and technical immunity
community have contributed I don't see
the current crop of leaders as having
the wisdom to wield such incredible
power I mean these are people who in my
opinion are getting worse and worse
at their job so that's one of the great
threats is is that we need to make sure
that that track record keeps going
another key problem is is that we've run
out of broad sources for broadly
distributed stable growth and people
keep talking about bringing the jobs
back and bringing growth back and my
belief is is that we actually have a
structural change in the economy in the
early 70s that we've been lying to
ourselves about with every gimmick known
to man and if we don't discover real
economic growth we're going to discover
what happens when humans don't have
economic growth that is broadly
distributed and it's not pretty I think
that there's also the risk that we're
going to lose a world that has been
bipolar and even unipolar in terms of
military strength after World War Two
and a multipolar world is a frightening
prospect not because you don't want many
voices to have a say but because the
game theory of a multipolar world is
entirely unstable and so things that we
used to take for granted when
it was the Cold War with two players
it's not clear what happens when you
make it ten player or 13 player games
where lots of people have credible
threats and everybody's trying to guess
which alliances are going to break I
mean just game theoretically we're
headed to a very unstable situation
which I'm not excited about I would like
to keep a world in which you know if
it's the US and China so be it but that
the number of major players is kept to a
relatively small number even though
something in all of us would like a more
democratic world I don't think the game
theory works and you talked about kind
of a sense of a kind of hollowing out of
politics and I think you've spoken
before about the sense that these
systems get weaker and weaker as they
continue it seems that as time has gone
on that the choices that were being
given in the political system get weaker
and weaker well because you're driving
you're systematically driving out the
people who should be trying to lead
you're making it so unpleasant to hold
real opinions to have real integrity
you're driving the costs of the specific
group of people we need so that instead
the only people who are going to show up
are the people that we should fear most
and why does that happen because the
sort of people we need are likely to be
independent thinkers and institutions
are terrified of independent thinkers an
independent thinker can reverse course
change their mind take a totally
different direction for a better or for
worse Donald Trump has a lot of
independent thinker in him you may not
like his independent thoughts but you
you're not going to easily cage him in a
perspective he's gonna break out of
every cognitive prison that you put in
front of him okay imagine that you had
somebody who was had a great deal more
wisdom and a lot more foresight than
Donald Trump but who wanted to be very
nimble who did not want complete
transparency when trying to negotiate a
trade treaty who was acting in the
better interests of most of the citizens
of his country but needed some
privacy for his family for his own
failings or potentially you know for her
weaknesses maybe because this was her
first time you know on a national stage
even if that person was the right person
for the job in such circumstances you
need to have something that is more
decent to the kind of people that we
need for leadership and what you have is
a world which has been throwing up
candidates that are broadly acceptable
to the institution's we need candidates
who are broadly unacceptable to
institutions its most important like any
candidate that is broadly acceptable to
the institutions to me is dead on
arrival I don't mean that everyone who
is not acceptable to the institution's
is somebody I would like to vote for but
the subset of people that I'm interested
in should be broadly unacceptable to the
major institutions across the board both
left and right something a bit like the
Groucho Marx quote that wouldn't want to
be part of a club that would have me as
a member
well the institution's don't want to
reform and so it's rational to me I
don't I don't think it's quite that I
think that the idea is that there's two
games here there's trying to get the
best deck chairs on the Titanic and
there's trying to rescue the ship and in
general nobody can think of how to
rescue the ship which is a daunting task
so instead what we're doing is we're
fighting for position in a losing game
and it's important that that stop so
you're talking about a different way of
thinking people who have a different way
of thinking is that what characterizes
the members of the IDW it's hard to say
I mean I would say that everybody in the
IDW is fairly disagreeable in the sense
of the big five personality inventory so
can you hold a position when you're the
only person in a room that believes that
thing like it's you versus a hundred
people I would say almost everybody in
the core of the IDW is capable of
holding a position where everyone is
against you and I think that that trait
is extremely rare something that's been
talked about
before is that in a way the people in
the IDW have been selected for like a
lot of them have had quite high-profile
encounters you look at Sam Harris with
Ben Affleck or you look at Brett
Weinstein and there's a sense that
they've in some way had to live out
their ideas there's a sense of bravery
that they've had to stick up for
themselves
Jordan Peterson and C 16 I mean you
could you can list a lot of times where
as you said they had to be that one
person who was thinking a certain thing
you know I mean I think I made the point
probably on the Rubin report that what's
going on is that when you ask any large
collection of people to salute a
nonsensical flag and pledge allegiance
to it and more or less everyone makes
the calculation I guess if this is going
to get me through my day I'll salute any
flag and you've got the one gal or one
guy who doesn't want to well my
observation is that that person is
usually sitting on an entire mountain of
interesting thoughts that they don't
have the freedom to simply make a
convenience readjustment and so from
that perspective yeah in general if you
ask a thousand people to salute a flag
that makes no sense and tell them that
they'll be incentivize you'll get a
thousand-dollar check at the end or you
know you won't lose your job and
somebody stands up and says no way I'm
getting out of here do what you want
that person is usually much more
interesting than just being a contrarian
that person is usually saying no because
they've got an entire worldview that is
built by hand and and bespoke
and so that's why this method of finding
people has been relatively fruitful it's
people who don't back down usually don't
back down for a reason because there's
every reason just to go along and what
is what is the nature of that kind of
ideology that's the thing that unites
the thing that unites I guess the IDW at
the moment is a resistance to a certain
type of thinking or a certain type of
ideological thinking especially in the
media how would you define that that
thinking well it means very simple
here are two characteristics that I
think you'd find in almost any member of
the IBEW almost every member of the IDW
that I can think of is going to have
very positive responses to things that
come out of Muslim culture and almost
every member of the IDW is going to have
a sense that there is a link between
Islam and terror that is active at the
moment that is not active at the same
level for any other group terror against
civilians okay well these are two simple
principles which is you've got a very
large religion most people in that
religion are just like everybody else
perfectly lovely people you've got a
dangerous subculture in the religion
it's size is you know is open for
question but there are a lot of people
who are flummoxed why is it that I can't
observe that somebody is saying allahu
akbar after a mass killing the news
reports that somebody's said something
in a foreign language or somebody said
god is great you know well you're not
really reporting the news are you so
that that that that rankles and on the
other hand you can't have people saying
okay muslims are a problem that's not
going to work either so you'll simply
find that there are these core balances
that people in the IDW I think are
better at striking which is like we
don't want to be closed borders we don't
want to be open borders immigrants
aren't simply positive hard-working
people who contribute to our economy and
they're not simply negative you know
gang members and welfare queens whatever
these positions are this is how the
mainstream has been fighting through
these idiocy x' for years and the people
in the IDW in general hold relatively
moderate perspectives and I think that
that's it's bizarre that it
distinguishes us that we're willing to
hold moderate perspective
in public where the media is trying to
drag us to it either they're communists
or they're fascists either these people
are religious whack-jobs or they're
atheist nihilists well in general no
these are people who are balancing
competing perspectives they're engaging
in a dialectic and it is strange that
there is no training for holding those
positions in public when the awesome
power of the media is to miss portray
everybody who attempts to find me Oh
Graham and Dave Rubin said that pretty
much anyone who is trying to think
beyond ideology so he was talking to his
viewers and saying you're part of the
intellectual dark web if you're prepared
to think about these things in a similar
way do you do you agree with that do you
think it's a bigger movement than just
the names the figures who have been kind
of associated with it well there's sort
of what I would call IDW nation which is
the collection of people who's trying to
you know add to the conversation who
might not be part of the core group and
I think what I see there is it's not
enough to try to struggle outside of the
box you also have to balance like
there's this issue of decency you have
to both be willing to look at the world
for what it is not what you want it to
be and you also have to bring a kind of
decency you can't take the cheap easy
way out by saying you know our biology
predisposes us to violence and therefore
violence is a good thing or you know you
can't be xenophobic because you realize
that we can't be open borders and you
can't be open borders because you
realize that closed borders and a phobia
is nonsense you have to continue to
struggle and I think that that's an
important thing that people don't yet
understand that the IDW generally
speaking doesn't take the easy outs it
would prefer to struggle between two
competing ideas then simply sign up for
one or the other because it's clean you
in the the Rubin report I think with
your brother Brett you talked about how
we pretty much had a blank slate
we were starting from a blank slate
because all of the prefab answers
libertarianism socialism even capitalism
don't work or play themselves out for
game theoretic reasons could you explain
what that means and in if so what what
does that conversation start looking
like well think about any of the major
schools of thought that have failed to
carry the day it could be Austrian
economics it could be market socialism
it could be mercantilism it could be you
know hardcore capitalism whatever it is
the reason that none of these schools
has prevailed totally is that none of
these ways of thinking work under all
circumstances and you know people have
fantasies like you know that the free
market is the market always knows the
true value of everything
well even free marketeers should know
that markets fail for various reasons
like in the case of public goods so you
have to hybridize all of these extreme
positions in order to get anything that
functions and in biology you think of
this in terms of regulated expression
you might have different responses to
different environments but which
response is mounted depends on the
environments of should you have
different rules for free speech and war
time maybe you need a Supreme Court to
pretend that the Constitution has to be
interpreted a little bit more strictly
in times of war and then loosened up at
another time
so in general all of these very simple
answers the market is always right the
different democracy is always right
Healthcare and education arrack human
rights all of these things just don't
work because they're too simplistic to
carry the complexity of a modern society
there was a really sort of deceptively
simple but quite profound thing that
either you're Brett said as well which
was about how one thing that is very
difficult to survive market forces is
the pursuit of truth the truth was
corrupted
market forces and that seems to kind of
explain a lot of the crisis of
journalism as a lot of the crisis for
the educational institutions can you
explain a little bit more about why you
think that is well this goes back to a
point I made that the clearing price of
truth is far higher than the newspaper
reader was willing to pay so the idea is
that if you actually had real truth
would be very valuable to you and in
circumstances where you could act upon
it and on the other hand a lot of the
other truth is not very interesting and
so occasionally you find truths that
that can't command important price
because they're just too dull they're
not important so I do believe that in
part you should look at something like
journalism and realize that the business
model doesn't quite make sense but that
there might be ways in which we would be
better served for example independent
investigative journalists might be a
better force for finding out
institutional malfeasance than corporate
investigative journalists who might be
captured by virtue of the fact that you
have a mixed subscriber and advertiser
model I do think that sometimes you have
to treat truth as a public good and you
may have to decide that you are going to
pay for it not at the level that the
market will bear that amount of the
price at the market will bear but at a
higher price because it's in the long
term interest of your of your society of
survival I think that's very true in the
sciences it is important to realize that
scientists produce a public good which
is both inexhaustible in excludable and
often not patentable by virtue of
international intellectual property
issues and the most important group of
truth seekers are probably not the
journalists but the scientists and you
should be trying to figure out as a
society how to
those people from the market the problem
is is that the people who want that not
done are very powerful because they are
representing powerful institutional
interests so it's an uphill battle it
seems that the the phenomena of the IDW
is is part of this great intellectual
awakening I mean you're seeing people
being really hungry for long-form
content on YouTube 3-hour conversations
people are clearly hungry for a lot more
intellectual stimulation I don't
actually agree with this this is an idea
that I think Jordan has slightly wrong
so for a while I've been making the
point that there was a change between
writing for television was sort of the
lowest form of of an art and that
writing for movies allowed for real
character development but that the multi
season multi episode shows with very
long storylines actually has the
greatest character development and so
the the greatest writers are now writing
for TV the important thing to understand
is is that it's not just the advent of
long-form podcasting what it is is
having the courage to say something
using that medium you have long-form
podcasts that aren't attracting almost
anybody and the only reason that the IDW
is behaving in a different fashion is
that it's marrying the content that
brave people are starved for with the
change in technology and so in general
most things don't work in a three-hour
format what works in a three-hour format
is when you're living through what I'm
calling left car theism where the modern
left which is my side of the aisle has
gone so completely insane that people
are starved for normal conversation as
if it was some is that in the former
Soviet Union and so you have an
underground
work if you will that is supplying that
need for reality and the only reason
we're underground is because the
mainstream is pretending for the most
part not to notice that this phenomena
is existing which is fascinating and
where do you hope that this IDW
conversation will go in the future
well I hope it goes to the heart of
everything that is denying our ability
to use our eyes on our ears and our
minds as decent people if you're simply
observing the world as it is and you're
thinking about it with a big open heart
and you're trying to be decent about it
at the same time that you're trying to
provide for your family and concerned
about your country's welfare there's no
reason that you should be huddling in
the cupboard afraid that if anyone hears
that you think that men are different
from women that you're going to be
consigned to the dustbin of history and
fired for it it's absolutely essential
that people stop being terrorized for
holding garden-variety positions
you